<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
    <title>Asya Davydova Lewis - gains</title>
    <subtitle> </subtitle>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://asyaplugged.in/tags/gains/atom.xml"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://asyaplugged.in"/>
    <generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
    <updated>2024-02-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://asyaplugged.in/tags/gains/atom.xml</id>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Summer Gains</title>
        <published>2024-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-02-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://asyaplugged.in/know/drafts/summer-gains/"/>
        <id>https://asyaplugged.in/know/drafts/summer-gains/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://asyaplugged.in/know/drafts/summer-gains/">&lt;p&gt;what i did this summer&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>January Gains</title>
        <published>2024-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-02-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://asyaplugged.in/know/january-gains/"/>
        <id>https://asyaplugged.in/know/january-gains/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://asyaplugged.in/know/january-gains/">&lt;p&gt;While it may be a little on-the-nose to start a personal accountability blog series in a January, it just so happened that I got extraordinarily motivated this recent December 2023 by my little brother. I locked in, as he&#x27;d say, and as a result, saw some exciting changes on my smart scale:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3.3 lbs muscle growth&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;7.5 lbs fat loss&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aside from these encouraging metrics, I also have some personal achievements to be proud of:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;left smith machine in the past, committing to balancing that barbell!&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;went from DB bench press to short bar ;)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ate 60-90g protein &#x2F; day &lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;settled on a gym uniform that feels cute&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think it&#x27;s important to mention that the progress from this January isn&#x27;t fair to characterize as progress just from one single month. Over the years that I&#x27;ve held various gym memberships and worked towards having a solid fitness routine, I&#x27;ve experimented with a plethora of strategies and approaches, and made a lot of mistakes along the way. These mistakes were vital for me to make, without them I wouldn&#x27;t have all the information I do today. In general, I don&#x27;t think that most people take the time to honor the hard work of the &amp;quot;bumbling fool&amp;quot; period we all go through when focused on a specific goal. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My own &amp;quot;bumbling fool&amp;quot; era was rife with confusions about cardio vs strength, workout split questions, figuring out how to choose a PT, should I sync my workouts to my cycle, which gym do I prefer going to, getting over gym shyness, how to use machines, exercise form, exercise form, proper attire, injury prevention, and so on and so forth. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&#x27;s still plenty that I&#x27;m clueless about, and that&#x27;s what the actionable goal tracking is about. While sometimes numbers on the scale may not move (but recomp is occurring), sometimes even bodycomp numbers won&#x27;t move either – so by focusing on celebrating what I&#x27;ve actually done and learned in each month of my committed fitness journey should theoretically prevent me from losing wind in my sails if I hit a plateau when it comes to my quantitative goals.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;february-intentions&quot;&gt;February Intentions&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;continue recomp progress (not something I am confident I can control very well)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;bench the regular bar, even the smallest sets, or the 35lb training bar&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;improve VO2 max via kettlebell swings or other cardio after each training session&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;eat 80-135g protein &#x2F; day&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;spend less money on vegan protein shakes from the grocery store and try some protein powders for homemade protein shakes&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;find my comfort zone with calorie tracking for more control over recomp progress&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;settle on a 6-month training split&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;settle on a 6-month nutritional goal&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depending on how well my February accomplishments align with these intentions, I&#x27;d like March&#x2F;April to start bringing my functional goals into the horizon: calisthenics and breaking.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
</feed>
