<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
    <title>Asya Davydova Lewis - recurse-center</title>
    <subtitle> </subtitle>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://asyaplugged.in/tags/recurse-center/atom.xml"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://asyaplugged.in"/>
    <generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
    <updated>2022-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://asyaplugged.in/tags/recurse-center/atom.xml</id>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Recurse Center or Bootcamp?</title>
        <published>2022-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2022-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://asyaplugged.in/know/rc-or-bootcamp/"/>
        <id>https://asyaplugged.in/know/rc-or-bootcamp/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://asyaplugged.in/know/rc-or-bootcamp/">&lt;p&gt;Why and how you should apply to the Recurse Center
My friend Priya made a blog post called &amp;quot;Should I go to a coding bootcamp or self-study&amp;quot;, which inspired me to share my own experiences and thoughts on the matter.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-experience-to-expose-what-i-am-biased-towards&quot;&gt;My experience – to expose what I am biased towards&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I originally decided that I&#x27;d like to learn programming around 2012, when I wanted to make a Russian-language online platform similar to &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;asyaplugged.in&#x2F;know&#x2F;rc-or-bootcamp&#x2F;rookiemag.com&quot;&gt;Rookie Mag&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. I didn&#x27;t understand that one could get away with finding a sort of suitable wordpress theme, and once I did, I felt so passionately about my ideal project that I figured I&#x27;d need to pay a programmer to make the exact theme that I&#x27;d envisioned for the platform. I was also inspired by this weird Russian listicle website called &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;asyaplugged.in&#x2F;know&#x2F;rc-or-bootcamp&#x2F;w-o-s.ru&quot;&gt;W-O-S&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, I loved how each article had some different animations and floating elements, and I especially loved the interactive quizzes.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mention my inspiration for learning how to code as I think inspiration is imperative to take account of when deciding on the direction you will take it into the material world. My interest was in a counterculture of both Russian and American origins, and online media. So in 2015, I attended a mini course at the Moscow Coding School.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, first I took some introductory programming classes at Santa Monica College. At the time, the main prerequisite to any programming class was an introduction to computing as a whole. My homework assignment was to draw something in MS Paint. I hope this story can illuminate the reasons I recieved F (for failed) grades in my first year at SMC.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Moscow Coding School, I learned introductory HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and WebGL. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;bootcamp&quot;&gt;Bootcamp&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;self-study&quot;&gt;Self Study&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;recurse-center-application&quot;&gt;Recurse Center Application&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have pubilished &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;asyapluggedin&#x2F;rc&#x2F;blob&#x2F;master&#x2F;application&#x2F;application-2022.md&quot;&gt;my own application to rc on my github&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;recurse-center&quot;&gt;Recurse Center&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;self-doubt-and-imposter-syndrome&quot;&gt;Self Doubt and Imposter Syndrome&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;employment&quot;&gt;Employment&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;goals-and-outcomes&quot;&gt;Goals and Outcomes&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Recurse Center Report: Half Batch</title>
        <published>2022-08-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2022-08-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://asyaplugged.in/know/recurse-center-report-1/"/>
        <id>https://asyaplugged.in/know/recurse-center-report-1/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://asyaplugged.in/know/recurse-center-report-1/">&lt;p&gt;This Friday marks the mid-point of my batch at the Recurse Center&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#1&quot;&gt;1&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;sup&gt;. I am in a 12 week batch, meaning I have completed 30 out of 60 days of the programming retreat. I already feel like a different person and a better programmer than when I started, and figured that it could be helpful for others to hear about my experience.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because I intended to do a 12 week retreat from the very start, I will say that I was a little lax with planning my time to be at maximum efficiency. My main goal for the retreat was proving to myself that I enjoy regular programming and learning new things, even if they look very much strange, and feel very much challenging.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;weekly-reports&quot;&gt;Weekly Reports&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Recurse, batch members are encouraged to post text check-ins in their respective Zulip streams. Thanks to this practice, I have been able to track and share my progress, as well as stay accountable to myself and learn from the obstacles blocking my workflows.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;week-1&quot;&gt;Week 1&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to excuse myself from the requirement of writing any code in the first week, as it is quite an overwhelming and social week, but in retrospect I wish I had challenged myself a bit more, and at least refactored some code in the project that I applied to RC with, so that I could present it during Friday presentations. However, I did:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;work on &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;asyaplugged.in&#x2F;do&#x2F;sunshine-act&#x2F;&quot;&gt;sunshine act&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; pen and paper RPG game&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;write short bios of everyone so i could remember peoples names and personalities&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;experimented with check-in formatting&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;make a &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.are.na&#x2F;anastasia-davydova-lewis&#x2F;recurse-center-2022&quot;&gt;master channel on are.na&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for all my RC batch related research&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;attend a pairing workshop&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;made ~1 new friend.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;week-2&quot;&gt;Week 2&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I became a lot more comfortable with all the RC software, so I set out to program every day. Despite such a clear intention, I only commited code on 3 of the 5 days, as I ended up feeling quite drained by the frequent &amp;quot;coffee chats&amp;quot;, planning to work on other people&#x27;s projects, and attending the social events.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;attended the &amp;quot;Building your volutional muscles&amp;quot; workshop, enjoyed it very much&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;started learning &lt;code&gt;Go&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; for my TUI game, ascii tarot&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;got sidetracked from learning &lt;code&gt;Go&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; with elektronika project bc of embedded meeing&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;attended the creative coding, but failed at my task because of updated browser permissions issues in &lt;code&gt;p5.js&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;had a coffee chat with a career center staff member&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;presented&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;made ~6 new friends!&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;week-3&quot;&gt;Week 3&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learning Go felt a little out of left field, so I decided to spin up a &amp;quot;quick and dirty&amp;quot; static website. The theme I chose to base it off of was anything but quick to work with, however it did prove to make for some quite dirty coding work. Ultimately, I was pleased with my 4&#x2F;5 daily commits, as well as the fact that I didn&#x27;t have to poke around the Go reference documents for a short while.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;learned about &lt;code&gt;SQL&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;started working with &lt;code&gt;Zola&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; and the karzok theme, &lt;code&gt;npm&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; became the bane of my existence&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;met with a staff member to discuss time management and my struggle with &amp;quot;doing other peoples homework&amp;quot; instead of focusing on my own work&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;attended the &amp;quot;Balancing learning generously with your own work&amp;quot; workshop - really loved it&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;attended the &amp;quot;feelings check-in&amp;quot;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;made ~4 new friends.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;week-4&quot;&gt;Week 4&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attending the weekly intentions and reflections meetings was quite phenomenal. In general, I find intentionality incredibly meaningful and valuable in my own routine, so sharing such a practice with fellow Recursers changed my entire experience. I felt a lot closer to the community, and struggled less with accountability.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another big change was replacing my coffee chat bot with the pairing bot. I noticed that the daily chit-chat meetings spawned by the coffee chat bot took a lot of energy out of me, but didn&#x27;t translate into a sense of satisfaction with how much I was learning programming or making progress on a project, be it mine or someone elses. Switching up the bots helped a lot, as I could at the very least look at somebody else&#x27;s code and ask about their goals at RC, rather than talk about our outside hobbies for an hour.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;started attending weekly intentions and reflections&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;presented during career panel&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;replaced coffee chat bot with pairing bot&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;shipped my personal website&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;paired with people on their projects, which was very rewarding.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;got some excellent pointers on Go from someone who has worked at the Go team&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;had a meeting with the career center&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;made ~4 new friends.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;week-5&quot;&gt;Week 5&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was the week I realized I needed to quickly make friends with everyone from the previous batch, which was ending the following week. I wish I had been more organized about my interactions with other people, as that&#x27;s really one of the most valuable aspects of RC. Even if you do not work on something together, it&#x27;s nice to at least get to know each other a little.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also set out to have a &amp;quot;solo&amp;quot; day where I wouldn&#x27;t attend any meetings or events, and just focus on some deep work. This was a good idea, and helped me feel more in control of my productivity.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;paired a bit&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;made progress on my website&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;went to the gym a lot&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;did some leetcode problems&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;strengthened ~2 of my existing RC friendships.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;week-6&quot;&gt;Week 6&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a long-standing tradition at RC to write &amp;quot;niceties&amp;quot; to members of the ending batch. I had 42 Recursers to write them for, as well as some extra for staff, which took a lot of time and effort. In the process I realized there were different types of Recursers – the very socially active, the more heads-down ultra-productive ones, the ones that host specialized events, and the ones that don&#x27;t participate in the community very much. I realized that despite my own feelings about my subpar progress, I myself was a relatively successful Recurser, as I made the retreat&#x27;s experience inspiring and fun for other members. Writing the niceties helped me reconsider my own goals and expectations of myself. I stopped worrying about completing a specific amount of leetcode problems or github commits, and decided to focus more on positively contributing to the experience of those currently at RC.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;completed niceties&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;made checkin and reflection templates for obsidian&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;began tinkering in hardware discussion groups&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;quit the google ux certificate coursera course bc didn&#x27;t have the patience to learn things i already know for $30&#x2F;mo&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;finally a successful creative coding project&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;wrote blog post for incoming batch as i decided to host creative coding going forward&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;made ~4 new friends!&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;takeaways&quot;&gt;Takeaways&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In these six weeks, the accomplishment I am most proud of is a sense of confidence in my ability to program, and my identity as a programmer. So many of my friends will sometimes say that they are not qualified for a project because they have limited experience programming – I cannot imagine doing this myself anymore. I would rather let the hardware say &amp;quot;no!&amp;quot; to me by breaking, than to say no to it first myself. I&#x27;ve learned that the only way to tackle the unknown is with curiosity – it is best friends with bravery anyway, so bravery will swiftly follow wherever curiousity goes.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Concrete accomplishments, however:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gave two talks&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Got a lot better at git&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mastered templating in Obsidian&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Configured my VSCode dev environment to work well with remote collaborative versioning workflows&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shipped a static website&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learned a lot of new things about JavaScript, Sass, Go, Rust, Tera, SQL, and shaders.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#x27;m very grateful for the chance to make so many new friends, too. Next week, the incoming batch will arrive. I am excited to show them around and host some events. I do not at all feel ready to take a senior post, but nonetheless I am curious how it will go in any event.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;footnote-definition&quot; id=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-definition-label&quot;&gt;1&lt;&#x2F;sup&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the Recurse Center? You&#x27;d probably learn best from their own &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.recurse.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;website&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Creative Coding at RC</title>
        <published>2022-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2022-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://asyaplugged.in/know/rc-creative-coding/"/>
        <id>https://asyaplugged.in/know/rc-creative-coding/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://asyaplugged.in/know/rc-creative-coding/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;introduction-credits&quot;&gt;Introduction &amp;amp; Credits&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the guide for the Creative Coding Meetup at the Virtual Recurse Center.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The meetup was started by &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;rfong.github.io&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Ray Fong&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, then led by &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;aturley&quot;&gt;Andrew Joseph Turley&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, who passed the torch to &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;Plasma-Vortex&quot;&gt;Howard Halim&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, who finally passed it to me.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;recurse.zulipchat.com&#x2F;#narrow&#x2F;stream&#x2F;224779-creative-coding&quot;&gt;creative-coding&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; Zulip stream has messages going all the way back to February 20, with the first one from &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;solsarratea.world&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Sol Sarratea&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. We now coordinate in another stream, &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;recurse.zulipchat.com&#x2F;#narrow&#x2F;stream&#x2F;19042-397-Bridge&#x2F;topic&#x2F;Creative.20Coding.20Meetup&quot;&gt;Creative Coding Meetup&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-happens-at-creative-coding&quot;&gt;What happens at Creative Coding?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each week a random prompt is picked, then we spend 90 minutes making something and meet back up to share what we made. Don&#x27;t worry about perfectionism, just come have fun.
Here are some of the generators we have used to produce creative prompts:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;stoney.sb.org&#x2F;eno&#x2F;oblique.html&quot;&gt;Oblique Strategies&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;codepen.io&#x2F;jacob4&#x2F;full&#x2F;EVqeWM&quot;&gt;Random Shakespeare Quote Generator&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;perchance.org&#x2F;emoji&quot;&gt;perchance Random Emoji Generator&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (set amount to 3, check &amp;quot;unique?&amp;quot; box)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can use whatever language or tools you are comfortable or uncomfortable with.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creativity manifests in different ways, so don&#x27;t feel restricted to making something visual, &amp;quot;artistic&amp;quot;, or even related to the chosen prompt. This is the place to make whatever your heart and mind desires!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some common choices:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;editor.p5js.org&#x2F;&quot;&gt;editor.p5js.org&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;codepen.io&#x2F;&quot;&gt;codepen.io&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.shadertoy.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;shadertoy.com&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;glitch.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;glitch.com&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;arcade.makecode.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;arcade.makecode.com&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coordinate in the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;recurse.zulipchat.com&#x2F;#narrow&#x2F;stream&#x2F;19042-397-Bridge&#x2F;topic&#x2F;Creative.20Coding.20Meetup&quot;&gt;Creative Coding Zulip topic&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.
Showing off your work is encouraged!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;resources&quot;&gt;Resources&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am leisurely amalgamating a lot of materials on an &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.are.na&#x2F;anastasia-davydova-lewis&#x2F;creative-coding-for-all&quot;&gt;Are.na page, creative-coding-for-all.&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; Feel free to add to it! I also have some more structured resources to peruse here:
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;misc-inspiration&quot;&gt;Misc Inspiration&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;paytonturnage.com&#x2F;writing&#x2F;generating-art-with-haskell&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Generative Art with Haskell&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;experiments.withgoogle.com&#x2F;collection&#x2F;chrome&quot;&gt;Chrome Experiments&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;css-resources&quot;&gt;CSS Resources&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;colorffy.com&#x2F;text-gradient-generator&quot;&gt;CSS text gradient generator&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;shadows.brumm.af&#x2F;&quot;&gt;CSS box shadow generator&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;9elements.github.io&#x2F;fancy-border-radius&#x2F;&quot;&gt;9elements – Fancy border radius generator&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;haikei.app&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Haikei – SVG generator&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;haikei.app&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Mesh Gradients by CSS Hero&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;min-max-calculator.9elements.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;9elements – Fluid Typography without media queries via min-max value&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;ui.glass&#x2F;generator&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Glassmorphism generator&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;ml-art-resources&quot;&gt;ML Art Resources&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kadenze &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.kadenze.com&#x2F;courses&#x2F;creative-applications-of-deep-learning-with-tensorflow&#x2F;info&quot;&gt;Creative Applications of Deep Learning with TensorFlow&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; class&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;some-ucla-design-media-class-websites-with-their-own-resource-reference-collections&quot;&gt;Some UCLA Design | Media Class Websites with their own resource &#x2F; reference collections&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;pkmital.com&#x2F;home&#x2F;2021&#x2F;09&#x2F;01&#x2F;ucla-course-on-cultural-appropriation-with-machine-learning&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Cultural Appropriation with Machine Learning&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;classes.dma.ucla.edu&#x2F;Fall21&#x2F;172&#x2F;?page_id=101&quot;&gt;Interactive Animation in Unity3D&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;lmccart.github.io&#x2F;DMA171-disability-design-web&#x2F;#resources&quot;&gt;Disability, Design, and the Web&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;classes.dma.ucla.edu&#x2F;Fall21&#x2F;289-2&#x2F;&quot;&gt;50 Years of Software Artists: Plotter Drawings to Non-fungible Tokens&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;classes.dma.ucla.edu&#x2F;Fall21&#x2F;152&#x2F;resources&quot;&gt;Tangible Media&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; – intro to working creatively with electronics.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;classes.dma.ucla.edu&#x2F;Winter21&#x2F;28&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Interactivity&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; – intro Processing class taught by Casey Reas, co-creator of Processing.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;classes.dma.ucla.edu&#x2F;Fall19&#x2F;161&#x2F;#resources&quot;&gt;Network Media&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; – html+css+js+p5.js taught by Lauren McCarthy, creator of p5.js.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recommend checking out the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;classes.dma.ucla.edu&#x2F;?cTerm=Winter&amp;amp;cYear=2021&quot;&gt;past versions of core DMA classes&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, as each one has its own website with varying resource lists.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;history-context-of-media-art-generative-art-creative-coding&quot;&gt;History, Context of Media Art, Generative Art, Creative Coding&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.are.na&#x2F;anastasia-davydova-lewis&#x2F;ucla-dma101-design-media-arts&quot;&gt;My Are.na class materials archive from the Media Art 101 class&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;quot;When the Machine Made Art: The Troubled History of Computer Art&amp;quot;, by Grant D. Taylor&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;quot;Creative Code: Aesthetics + Computation&amp;quot; by John Maeda&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;quot;Generative Design&amp;quot; by Benedikt Groß, Hartmut Bohnacker, Julia Laub&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;misc-creative-coders-and-their-work&quot;&gt;misc creative coders and their work&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Vera_Moln%C3%A1r&quot;&gt;Vera Molnár&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Harold Cohen&#x27;s AARON&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;web.archive.org&#x2F;web&#x2F;20161103091706&#x2F;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;silverbuffalo.org&#x2F;NAA-NativeIT.html&quot;&gt;Silver Buffalo on Native American IT&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;blacktransarchive.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;The Black Trans Archive&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;web.archive.org&#x2F;web&#x2F;20020323214647&#x2F;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;neutralground.sk.ca&#x2F;artistprojects&#x2F;spiderlanguage&#x2F;index.html&quot;&gt;Spider Language&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; – a First Nations contemporary art web&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;super-sad-googles.glitch.me&#x2F;&quot;&gt;super sad googles&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;facework.app&#x2F;&quot;&gt;facework.app&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;store.steampowered.com&#x2F;app&#x2F;295790&#x2F;Never_Alone_Kisima_Ingitchuna&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Never Alone on Steam&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; inspired by Donna Haraway&#x27;s &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.dukeupress.edu&#x2F;staying-with-the-trouble&quot;&gt;Staying with the Trouble: Making Kin in the Chthulucene&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.damonzucconi.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Damon Zucconi&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;brutalistwebsites.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Brutalist Websites&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;lynnandtonic.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Lynn Fisher&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;a-website-is-a-room.net&#x2F;&quot;&gt;a website is a room&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; archive of websites exploring the browser as a space&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.werkplaatstypografie.org&#x2F;#vitrine:https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.werkplaatstypografie.org&#x2F;vitrine&#x2F;archive&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Werkplaatz Typographie Vitrine Archive&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;x20xx.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;x20xx.com&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;want-to-contribute-to-this-guide&quot;&gt;Want to contribute to this guide?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Submit &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;asyapluggedin&#x2F;asyaplugged.in&#x2F;blob&#x2F;main&#x2F;content&#x2F;know&#x2F;2022-08-04-rc-creative-coding.md&quot;&gt;a pull request in the github repo&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for this blog.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
</feed>
