<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
    <title>Asya Davydova Lewis - wellness</title>
    <subtitle> </subtitle>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://asyaplugged.in/tags/wellness/atom.xml"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://asyaplugged.in"/>
    <generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
    <updated>2025-11-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://asyaplugged.in/tags/wellness/atom.xml</id>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>I have endometriosis.</title>
        <published>2025-11-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2025-11-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://asyaplugged.in/know/endometriosis/"/>
        <id>https://asyaplugged.in/know/endometriosis/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://asyaplugged.in/know/endometriosis/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;Intro&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spent most of 2025 disabled from stage II deep infiltarting endometriosis.
Endometriosis is estimated to affect 11%-15% of women aged 15-44. The condition has even been documented in men (fewer than 20 cases, but nonetheless). Widely dismissed as &amp;quot;just a bad period&amp;quot;, it is a scary inflammatory disease that spans far beyond purely gynecological medical scope. Endometriosis is a social issue, too. The stigma surrounding women&#x27;s health, lack of societal awareness, lackluster research, and overall societal expectations that ignore the reality of infradian cycles all contribute to the gaslighting and delays in appropriate care that almost all endometriosis patients experience. 
The average diagnostic delay can be from 7 to 11 years. I didn&#x27;t realize I had endo until I was 29, but from the moment I suspected it, it only took me a 1.5 months to receive a diagnosis via MRI, and only 8 months until I was carted into the operating room while &amp;quot;Mea Culpa&amp;quot; by Engima accompanied my slow fade into anesthesiological bliss.
I am writing this blog post with the hope that it reduces guesswork for somebody else. Whether you suspect you have endometriosis, another hormonal or pelvic issue, or whether you just know some women, work with them, or interact with people at all, learning more about the issue could be the difference between a lifetime of suffering through complications and an early intervention strategy.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;medical-timeline-summary&quot;&gt;Medical Timeline Summary&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was able to fast-track my progression towards an excision surgery due to several factors I will be getting into later, and here it is exactly:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jan 21 Period starts (weird at first, then normal)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jan 25 Period ends and severe pain persists&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jan 31  PCP online visit&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feb 4 Ultrasound
Results show lesions on both ovaries&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feb 13 PCP issued MRI order&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feb 14 OBGYN visit, prescribed Norethindrone&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;March 10 MRI scan
DIE confirmed, lesion size confirmed, kissing ovaries imaged&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;March 18 GYN  ONC visit&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;March 21 video OBGYN&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;March 26th MIGS consultation&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;May 13 second pelvic ultrasound
Lesion size change recorded&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;July 30 MIGS pre-op&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;August 21 MIGS excision surgery&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sep 5 post-op appointment&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PCP visit to summarize&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;slow-collapse-is-something-wrong&quot;&gt;Slow Collapse: Is Something Wrong?&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In November of 2024, I began to feel somewhat burnt out and lethargic. I attributed this to the stress of studying for EMT exams, but even asking my psychiatrist for beta-blockers didn&#x27;t seem to completely remediate the issue. Even with managed anxiety, I was still slowly, but surely developing some sort of anhedonia. I then had a terribly uncomfortable and painful period, which I ignored because I was trying to be functional, and I didn&#x27;t want to complicate things with my medical training beyond the student accomodations I had already requested for my auditory processing issues that already felt needlessly bureaucratic and complicated. My December period was unremarkable, so I thought all was fine. The ovaries will alternate each menstrual cycle, so I knew that I should just keep an eye out for what happens once my &amp;quot;bad&amp;quot; ovary menstruates again. 
I would typically experience premenstrual cramps 1-2 days prior to the first day of my period (when blood appears). In January of 2025, however, I had a lot of (pre-menstrual?) pain in my lower back, which was concerning. After about a week, I finally got my period and sighed with relief that everything is fine, I&#x27;m not dying, it&#x27;s just my period. As time passed, my concerns came back: I didn&#x27;t see much blood the first day, and what I did see was abnormally dark and thick. The second day there was nothing, and only on the third day did it feel like a more normal period. What else was strange – the pain was present the entire time.
My &amp;quot;normal-ish&amp;quot; period ended, but the pain never went away. I was in pain about 80% of the time, easing up during the day. It would come back with intensity towards the evening and keep me from falling asleep, sometimes it would wake me up at night and I wouldn&#x27;t be able to fall back asleep.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was afraid to eat. My appetite completely disappeared and I didn&#x27;t even want to look at fried, sweet, fatty, carb-rich, salty or spicy foods. I could only think about tea, soup and smoothies, but I no longer had any energy to cook myself soup.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-brca-layer-still-writing&quot;&gt;The BRCA Layer (still writing...)&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;oh no i also have brca
oh yay i have a bunch of doctores that can help make this all speed up&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;also i studied ems and have flexible work hours so i was able to call for cancellations a lot.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;care-timeline&quot;&gt;Care Timeline&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;pre-excision-pain-management-still-writing&quot;&gt;Pre-excision Pain Management (still writing...)&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;tldr TAKE NAPROXEN BABE
pain became structural in daily life: fatigue, nausea, constipation, hormonal chaos. loss of exercise tolerance, dizziness, brain fog, POTS overlap. ambition vs chronic pain and chronic fatigue. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;endometriosis-excision-surgery&quot;&gt;Endometriosis Excision Surgery&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ritu Salani, MD Gyn Onc - Called Dr Mehta&#x27;s office on my behalf &amp;lt;3&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sukrant K. Mehta, MD (Primary Surgeon, MIGS) ABSOLUTE ICON&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Esther Wu, MD (Surgeon 1st Assist - Resident)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neil H.Sagrado, CRNA&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John T. Chalabi, MD (Anesthesiologist)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kathleeh H, RN&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sasha P, RN&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;so-are-you-better-now&quot;&gt;So are you better now?&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do I feel better than I did at the start of 2025? Absolutely. I can sleep through the night with no disturbances from pain. I can eat mostly whatever I&#x27;d like. I rarely have strange sensations in my pelvis, legs, lower back or abdomen now. I am not taking NSAIDs at a rate that is dangerous to my stomach lining. I have put away my heating pad in the shape of a giant diaper and not needed to take it out of the drawer since I&#x27;ve recovered from surgery.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I still have endometriosis, and I always will. I still have flare days. I have naproxen in my bedside table and purse. My electric blanket is always plugged in, and I often turn on the heated seats when driving in the car. I include pelvic floor exercises in my gym routine. I regularly attend breathwork classes and have been focusing more on somatic modalities for therapeutic release. I say no to a lot of opportunities and invitations. I take a low dose of a GLP medication. I&#x27;m still in the turbulent IUD adjustment phase as I wait for my hormonal cycle to stabilize. And I am still frequenting the doctor&#x27;s office for my BRCA prevention plan and my POTS complaints. I am still learning about the intricacies of my neurodivergence and the relationship it has to my &amp;quot;physical&amp;quot; health. (I&#x27;m not a dualist. You can leave the Descartes at the door.)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So am I better? Yes. But I&#x27;m not &amp;quot;fine&amp;quot;, and I never will be, and I don&#x27;t plan to hide that.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-others-should-know-still-writing&quot;&gt;What others should know (still writing...)&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;everything&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Everything is Boring: Robin Arnott on Meditation &amp; Gaming</title>
        <published>2022-08-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2022-09-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://asyaplugged.in/know/everything-is-boring/"/>
        <id>https://asyaplugged.in/know/everything-is-boring/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://asyaplugged.in/know/everything-is-boring/">&lt;div class=&quot;video-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube-nocookie.com&#x2F;embed&#x2F;n94J-9YxZPc&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;&#x2F;iframe&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I experienced a rather significant personal paradigm shift after Robin Arnott&#x27;s presentation &amp;quot;Everything is Boring&amp;quot; at the BDYHAX conference on February 24th, 2019. I have several versions of hand-written notes on it, and have spent countless late nights gesticulating on and on about the premise, so I figured to publish my notes (something between an inaccurate summary and personal comments) and suavely drop a hyperlink any time the itch to transmute this paradigm strikes, instead of acting like &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;knowyourmeme.com&#x2F;memes&#x2F;pepe-silvia&quot;&gt;this&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk focuses on the issue at the center of the wellness-meditation economy: everything is boring. Using a psychological framework from Ken Wilber, it analyzes the wellness economy&#x27;s own relative &amp;quot;health&amp;quot;, and demonstrates that both wellness and successful consumer interfaces have a much stronger connection to passion-based areas like entertainment, music and gaming, rather than mass infrastructure like medicine or workforce training.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robin: if you&#x27;re reading this, please respond to my emails – I would love to have access to the slides from this talk. It&#x27;s great that there&#x27;s now a video recording available, but I am struggling to find the proper chart images the talk is based on.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;Introduction&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arnott is the CEO and cofounder of Andromeda Entertainment, a gaming publishing company focused on titles that draw inspiration from wellness, i.e. games that enrich players lives in meaningful ways, rather than just baiting and distracting them.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He has spoken quite a bit about game design as a mechanism for transcendence, but this talk focuses on Ken Wilber&#x27;s Integral Theory – a psychological theory that can be used not only for understanding oneself and the people around us, but also understanding trends in culture learning how to aid the psychological developments of culture at large.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;integral-psychology&quot;&gt;Integral Psychology&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arnott believes one of the main issues with health technologies and the way we treat our bodies is it that it can be pretty joyless, boring and uninspiring. Analyzing current paradigms of health technologies, health economies, and our relationship with our body as a whole through the frame of Integral psychology offers some not-so-boring steps forward.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;images.squarespace-cdn.com&#x2F;content&#x2F;v1&#x2F;51a0ef99e4b0673a4c034ab8&#x2F;1373221911253-I9CKMOFPCM86G3TNULLF&#x2F;Screen-Shot-2013-03-29-at-7.07.30-PM.png&quot; alt=&quot;integral theory map&quot;&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Figure 1. Ken Wilber&#x27;s Integral Psychology theory map.&lt;&#x2F;figcaption&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Figure 2. &amp;quot;Stages of Consciousness&amp;quot; map.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arnott highlights three color-coded stages as separate paradigms from each of them:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;orange paradigm: bureaucratic, scientific, evidence based&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;green paradigm: decentralized, pluralistic, postmodern, egalitarian&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;teal paradigm: integrated, evolving the present moment&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;have-you-ever-lied&quot;&gt;Have you ever lied?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&#x27;s say, you tell some huge lie, for example you have been cheating on your partner and you don&#x27;t tell them the truth. What are the consequences of this lie? How does it make you feel? How much does it affect other decisions you make? Your entire life becomes predicated on this one lie. You lose confidence in your decision-making and your actions. You cannot build a life on top of a foundation comprised of a lie.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;medical-economy&quot;&gt;Medical Economy&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The medical economy operates on the social lie that the medical system has the answer to overcoming death. The orange medical system maintains the lie that YOU SHOULD NOT DIE.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;medical-gaze&quot;&gt;Medical Gaze&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This argument reminds me of the &amp;quot;medical gaze&amp;quot;, the practice of objectifying the body of the patient as separate from their personal identity, coined by Michel Foucault&#x27;s in &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;The_Birth_of_the_Clinic&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;Birth of the Clinic&amp;quot;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, which interrogates the dehumanization foundational to modern medicine, as well as the reasons why the scientific advances in medicine and healthcare have not succeeded in abolishing sickness and resolving the problems of humanity.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-green-paradigm-in-the-wellness-economy&quot;&gt;The green paradigm in the wellness economy&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The wellness paradigm of meditation apps with their condescending &amp;quot;nudge&amp;quot; notifications, &amp;quot;should&amp;quot;-ing you, is also predicated on a lie. It condescends and infantilizes users under the false pretense that
SOMETHING IS WRONG WITH YOU.
You need to &amp;quot;get better&amp;quot;. If you miss a day, you are a failure. Your habits are pathologized when they do not serve the app&#x27;s interests of high user engagement and retention.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, how often do you pick up your phone to use a self-improvement app? How much time per day do you spend on this app category? There&#x27;s mounds of UX research showing that this app category does not perform well in the screen time olympics. 
But what apps do you gravitate towards when you want to feel better? Spotify. Candy Crush. Snapchat. Tiktok.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you ever gone to a concert &amp;amp; felt spiritually transformed?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;ux-as-infantilization&quot;&gt;UX as Infantilization&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arnott&#x27;s focus on &amp;quot;condescending infantilism&amp;quot; reminds me of Jesse Baron&#x27;s essay &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;reallifemag.com&#x2F;the-babysitters-club&#x2F;&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;The Babysitters Club&amp;quot;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-teal-paradigm-in-the-next-economy-of-health&quot;&gt;The teal paradigm in the next economy of health&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next economy of health is based in joy and transformation.
Body - Mind is an expression of Truth.
Music, entertainment, and socializing are healing economy models.
They do not have a &amp;quot;should quality and your soul is open to them.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;th&gt;&lt;th style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Medicine&lt;&#x2F;th&gt;&lt;th style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Wellness&lt;&#x2F;th&gt;&lt;th style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;A new modality&lt;&#x2F;th&gt;&lt;&#x2F;tr&gt;&lt;&#x2F;thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Identity&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;individual&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;pluralistic data point in global database&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;spirit&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;&#x2F;tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Achievement&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;systematization&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;access&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;integrated wisdom&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;&#x2F;tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Relationship to Body&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;mechanical&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;purging trauma&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;maladaptive body patterns begin to dissolve&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;&#x2F;tr&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;tbody&gt;&lt;&#x2F;table&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
</feed>
